RG 062:062, Town of Hamden
Connecticut State Library
Town of Hamden records
1798-1978
bulk 1935-1978
Connecticut State Library
Hamden (Conn.)
18.75 cubic feet
East Plain Society rate book, 1798 and Health Department housing code enforcement files, 1968-1976; welfare files, 1935-1978; and Connecticut Child Study and Treatment Home file, 1955-1962.
RG062_062
T000331, 2013-008, and 2013-051
Historical Note
The town of Hamden was incorporated in May 1786 and was taken from New Haven.
Scope and Content
East Plain Society rate book, 1798 and Health Department housing code enforcement files, 1968-1976; welfare files, 1935-1978; and Connecticut Child Study and Treatment Home file, 1955-1962.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Child mental health services -- Connecticut; Connecticut Child Study and Treatment Home; High Meadows (Hospital: Hamden, Conn.); Housing -- Law and legislation -- Connecticut -- Hamden; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Hamden -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Hamden -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Hamden -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Hamden -- Registers; Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Hamden
Places:
Hamden (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
Welfare files (Accession 2013-008) are restricted by Connecticut General Statutes §1-210(b)(10), §17b-90, §42-471, and §45a-754. Boxes 3, 4, and 6 are further restricted due to water damage.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The welfare files in accession 2013-008 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library from the Town of Hamden Community Services Department on August 27, 2012.
Container List
- Records, 1798; 1935-1978
  - Rate book, East Plain Society, 1798; T000331 (Box 1)
  - Housing code enforcement files, Health Department, 1968-1976; T000331 (Box 2-7)
    Consists of inspection reports and related correspondence. Also includes administrative files.
    Enforcement files arranged alphabetically by street name.
  - Welfare files, 1935-1978; 2013-008
    These files are RESTRICTED. See Restrictions on Access note above.
    Case files are arranged numerically by case number.
    Case numbers 1601-1700, 2129-2450, and 2785-3840 were not transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
    - Welfare case files 1200-1334 (Box 1)
    - Welfare case files 1335-1399 (Box 2)
    - Welfare case files 1400-1600 (Box 3)
    - Welfare case files 1701-1741 (Box 4)
    - Welfare case files 1748-1901 (Box 5)
    - Welfare case files 1902-1949, 1972, 1978, 2101-2128 (Box 6)
    - Welfare case files 1950-2100, 2108 (Box 7)
    - Welfare case files 2451-2668 (Box 8)
    - Welfare case files 2669-2784 (Box 9)
    - Welfare case files 3841-4055 (Box 10)
    - Welfare case files 4057-4109 (Box 11)
    - Out of town inquiries, 1940-1945, 1950-1955 (Box 11)
    - Welfare budget expenditures, 1936-1948 (Box 12)
  - First Selectman - Connecticut Child Study and Treatment Home, 1955-1962; 1 folder; 2013-051 (Box Item 1)
    The Connecticut Child Study and Treatment Home is also known as High Meadows.
    The First Selectman served on the Advisory Committee to the Board of Trustees. The file includes meeting minutes and annual reports.